# Jose Luis Urrea Suarez

Carrera 47 # 52 Sur 110. Sabaneta, Antioquia - Colombia

Cellphone: +(57) 300 792 66 35

urreasuarez@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jlurrea

#### **SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

# Software Preseales Engineer | Technician Leader | Business Analyst

I am goal oriented, with communication skills, team working, responsible, respectful, honest, self managed, customer oriented and with resourceful spirit.

I have 20 years of experience in the software industry, understanding and solving customers problems. I have experience in analysis and design of software solutions in differents industries. I have experience in software developing, software architecture, technical feasibility analysis and cost estimation for the execution of software projects.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Leadership | Ability to solve problems | Customer service | Logic thinking | Analytical and critical thinking | Technical leadership.

JAVA Programming Language | C# | Oracle PL/SQL | Oracle Database | MySQL Database | SQL Server | Object Oriented Programming | Software Architecture | SCRUM Agile Methodology | Web Services | Enterprise Architect tool UML for business Modeling.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **AXEDE Corporation – Differentiation and Innovation Manager**

From April 2015 to present (Colombia)

I am part of the technical team in charge of developing the company's software products, to help in the productivity of the clients' processes. First, we define the product that solves a need, then we define the features of the product, the roadmap and finally the development of the software solution with agile methodologies and ensure quality product.

### **Environment:**

Java, Java Spring, JDK, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, Java Web services, API Rest, XML, JSON, NetBeans IDE, Eclipse IDE, JavaScript, Node JS, React JS, Webpack, CSS, HTML, Azure Cloud Platform.

### **MVM INGENIERIA Corporation – Senior Software Analyst**

From April 2014 to March 2015 (Colombia)

I was part of the development contractor team for a utilities services Company, where I was responsible to meet end user requirements, do the analysis and design of the software solution and create technical documentation. Development of the software solution and delivering to a quality team with unit tests. Also, support users of the solution.

#### **Environment:**

Java, Java Web Services, SoapUI for Java web services, API Rest, ORACLE, PL/SQL, Toad for Oracle, SQL.

## **AXEDE Corporation – Senior Software Developer**

From August 2005 to March 2014 (Colombia)

I was part of the research and development team of the company for development of new software products with CEBP extrategy (Communication Enable Business Process), where we combined software solutions integrated with communications platforms like Avaya, Cisco and Alcatel.

I was part of the development team of the inventory taken project for the retail contractor Exito Group, where I led the taking of users requirements, development of a solution with web services for web applications and PDA terminals and users support.

Also, I successfully supported the sales department of the company for the realization of software projects proposals, understanding customer requirements and the costs of the project regarding engineering resources.

#### **Environment:**

Java, Java Spring, JDK, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, Java Web services, API Rest, XML, JSON, NetBeans IDE, Eclipse IDE, JavaScript, Node JS, CSS, HTML, Azure Cloud Platform.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Computer Sciences East Catholic University (June 2001)
- Specialist Information Manager and Data Bases San Buenaventura University (June 2005)
- Oracle University: Architecture and Oracle Database Administration
- Oracle University: Program With PL/SQL
- Oracle University: ORACLE SOA SUITE 10G: SOA ESSENTIALS
- IBM Rational Software: Mastering Object-Oriented Analysis and Design with UML 2.0

- I attended the course *Pentaho BI Suite Bootcamp 2010 [San Francisco, CA], USA*, training about Business Intelligence Tools (BI).
- I attended the course *Cloud Essentials 2012 New York City, USA,* for Software as a Service (SaaS), Platform as a Service (PaaS) and Infrastructure as a Service (laaS).

# **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish (Native Language)
- English (Advanced C1)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Oracle Certification: Program With PL/SQL
- Oracle Certification: Oracle Certified Associate (OCA)
- Java Standard Edition Programmer